# **Evan Walter**

linkedin.com/in/-evanwalter • github.com/Evan-Walter • evanwalter.dev

### **PROFILE**

I am a web-focused Software Engineer. With over 10 years of experience delivering technical solutions, I am proficient with React, Node.js, and TypeScript. I began my transition from Electrical Engineering to Full Stack Engineering in 2019. With experience owning technical projects, I leverage leadership skills to serve teams.

# **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

React, Next.js, Node.js, Typescript, JavaScript, Redux, Express.js, Vue.js, jQuery, MySQL, MongoDB, Mongoose, NoSQL, GraphQL, Gatsby, Ruby on Rails, Plain Old Ruby, Python, HTML5, CSS3, Tailwind, Sass, SCSS, Less, Bootstrap, Git, GitHub, REST APIs, JSON, ecommerce, JavaScript Frameworks, JavaScript Libraries, Full Stack, Front End, Back End, PHP, Laravel, Docker, Bash, Shell Scripting, Linux, C/C++

### **EXPERIENCE**

### **Web Developer**

### GhostBed, Plantation, FL (Remote)

### February 2022—Present

- Migrate to a headless stack with React, Next.js, GraphQL, Craft CMS, and the Shopify e-commerce API
- Continuously improve the web application with new features, performance optimization, and testing
- Communicate across departments like marketing, design, and customer support
- · Report to Director of Engineering to grow technical skills, professional skills, and job responsibilities

### **Software Engineer**

#### Sole Proprietorship, Redding, CA (Remote and Local)

#### January 2021—Present

- Develop custom solutions with JavaScript, Python, HTML5, CSS3, and Liquid, written in Ruby on Rails
- Interface directly with clients to deliver front end web development and Wordpress development
- Manage client websites and assets with Python scripts, applications, and Amazon AWS Cloud API integration
- Optimize website performance by 20% along with git source control, theme kit, and data backups

### **Full Stack Software Engineer (Contract)**

### Rewired.one, London, UK (Remote)

#### September 2021-November 2021

- Implement requested client UI and UX features weekly in well-designed, testable code with full stack React, Node.js, Express, and MySQL
- Build quality, innovative, and fully performing software that complies with coding standards and technical design to execute the full software development life cycle (SDLC)
- Report to the project manager and leadership to define personal goals and mentorship

### **Electrical Designer**

### Electric Innovations, LLC, Redding, CA

### October 2019—January 2021

- Develop highly detailed, custom designs for a broad scope of new and existing systems, saving the company hundreds of hours on system maintenance and troubleshooting
- Deliver on time with tight deadlines
- · Align drawings with coding standards and conventions
- Perform job duties with excellence and with flexibility, with little direction, or with direct supervision
- · Communicate effectively with team members and clients as an outward-facing member of the team

### **Electrical Engineer**

## Newport News Shipbuilding, Newport News, VA

#### September 2016-September 2019

- · Create electrical designs for components, equipment, systems, and networks
- Improve key customer products with work package data, SAP programming, Visual Basic code, and Microsoft Excel spreadsheets
- Troubleshoot and test shipboard electrical solutions while working directly with customers

## **Junior Computer Engineer**

### ECS Federal, LLC, Arlington, VA

June 2015-March 2016

- Create a testing strategy that the team fully adopted as their new technical workflow
- Design software, firmware, and hardware with VHDL, FPGAs, Xilinx ISE, and Altera/Intel Quartus
- Integrate analog RF systems for low observables from the bottom up, including component level design, plate testing, system integration, and digital control
- Test equipment with technical instrumentation Modulation Analyzers, Oscilloscopes, Spectrum Analyzers, PNAs, Frequency Counters, and Logic Analyzers

#### **EDUCATION**

#### **Bachelor of Science in Electrical Engineering**

George Mason University • Fairfax, VA • May 2015

#### **ACTIVITIES**

- I am involved with local groups such as Redding Area Designers and Developers (RADD), Shasta Ruby User Group (SHRUG), and Startup Redding.
- · I teach kids computer programming.
- I enjoy outdoor activities, music, and spending time with family and friends.